Phone: (805) 390-9752
Website: www.ivanm.org
contact@ivanm.org

IVAN MARTINEZ

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Simi Valley, California 93065 United States of America

Creative individual who sets goals to meet current development demands. Certified in the field of web design and recognized by the Ventura County Regional Occupational Program. Uses design software such as Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to construct designs. Coded in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, PHP. Used software such as WordPress, Drupal, Magneto Cart, JQuery, and Laravel to accomplish tasks. Displayed skills in web design / development, workflow management and graphic design. Specialized in C++ programming over 3 years experience.

EDUCATION

High School Diploma, 2013

Santa Susana High School, Simi Valley, CA

- Worked on the school's website, managed content. Used programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
 Discussed projects with a team of students. Received certification as a web designer, in the Ventura county regional occupational program.
- Completed a senior project, 20 or more hours were spent on the task. Assembled a portfolio and wrote a report on internet development.

Moorpark College, 2013 - Present, Moorpark, CA

Associates In Social Sciences. Transfering towards a BS in Computer Science. Knowledge in procedural and object-orientated
programming using c++. Built computer science club website: enthusiasticprogrammers.com and hackathon website: hackmc.com.
Also took several IT courses including intro to networking security & Comptia A+ practice. Managed CS Club finances. President of
CS CLUB SPRING 2015-2016.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Gregory Media Inc. Militaryconnection.com, 250 E. Easy St Simi Valley, CA 2014-PRESENT

Web Designer & Technical Support

- Created Frontend / Newsletter designs, worked with Adobe photoshop and illustrator to create logos, email campaigns, banners, and
 website designs. Worked with Wordpress to make customized edits to blog section of the website.
- Managed backend development with Laravel PHP framework and BASH.
- Worked with several programming languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL to keep site with over 100,000 daily hits updated
- Knowledgable with online marketing skills such as SEO and Advertising, managed Google Analytics
- Administered Linux Dedicated Server, utilized network security knowledge to mitigate attacks.
- Provided Desktop support and backups, swapped out old hardware with new ones, provided networking support to small office.

RepWatch.co. Physical Therapy APP Consultant WESTLAKE VILLAGE CA 2016

Consulted Local Physical Therapy startup on FrontEnd APP Wireframes, Constructed Mockup using PHP LARAVEL.

Accomplishments:

• Demonstrated intuitive skills, helped plan front end updates, administered dedicated linux server, and worked with virtualization.

VOLUNTEER WORK

ST. ROSE OF LIMA, Simi Valley, CA 2010 - 2013

Local Church, Accepts volunteers for helping out the community. Non-profit Organization.

Volunteer

Assisted in the annual Dream cuisine event in Simi Valley, CA

SPECIAL CERTIFICATIONS / Acknowledgments

- Ventura County Regional Occupational Program Web Design Earned 2013
- NASA Aerospace Scholars Program for STEM Students Earned 2016
- ACM SOCAL Region Programming Competition / Progfest Programming Competition Contestant

COMPUTER SKILLS

Software:

Git, Microsoft Office Suite, Photoshop CS6, Illustrator CS6, After Effects Cs5, InDesign, Adobe Dreamweaver CS6, Sony Vegas Pro, Cinema 4D, Windows, Linux, Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian, Mac OSX

Programming Languages: HTML/5 (5 Yrs) ,CSS (5 Yrs) ,JavaScript (4 Yrs),PHP+SQL (4 Yrs)

,PYTHON (2 Yrs) ,C++ (3 Yrs) ,BASH (2 Yrs)

Security: Malware, Secure Programming, Network Security, Backups

Additional Skills: MYSQL/MARIADB Laravel, Virtualization, Web Hosting, SFTP, SSH